A Guide to the Papers of Edward L. Schrock, 1999-2004
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- Correspondence 1999-2004
  - Letters from Constituents 1999-2004
    - Interstate Waste October 2003 (Box-folder 21:25)
    - Iraq October 2003 (Box-folder 21:26)
    - Social Security October 2003 (Box-folder 21:27)
    - Various October 2003 (Box-folder 21:28)
    - Abortion November 2003 (Box-folder 21:29)
    - Airlines November 2003 (Box-folder 21:30)
    - Family and Medical Leave Inclusion Act November 2003 (Box-folder 21:31)
    - Gay Marriage November 2003 (Box-folder 21:32)
    - Iraq November 2003 (Box-folder 21:33)
    - Military / Veteran's Benefits November 2003 (Box-folder 21:34)
    - Stormwater Control November 2003 (Box-folder 21:35)
    - Survivor Benefit Plan November 2003 (Box-folder 21:36)
    - Ten Commandments Display November 2003 (Box-folder 21:37)
    - Various November 2003 (Box-folder 21:38)
    - Family and Medical Leave Inclusion December 2003 (Box-folder 21:39)
    - Southeast Crescent Authority December 2003 (Box-folder 21:40)
    - Various December 2003 (Box-folder 21:41)
    - Cancer 2003 (Box-folder 22:1)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation 2003 (Box-folder 22:2)
    - English Language 2003 (Box-folder 22:3)
    - Interstate Waste 2003 (Box-folder 22:4)
    - Iraq 2003 (Box-folder 22:5)
    - Medicare 2003 (Box-folder 22:6)
    - Millennium Challenge Account 2003 (Box-folder 22:7)
    - SBA 504 Loan Program 2003 (Box-folder 22:8)
    - Social Security / Medicare I 2003 (Box-folder 22:9)
    - Social Security / Medicare II 2003 (Box-folder 22:10)
    - Social Security / Medicare III 2003 (Box-folder 22:11)
    - Transportation 2003 (Box-folder 22:12)
    - Various 2003 (Box-folder 22:13)
    - Gasoline January 2004 (Box-folder 22:14)
    - Military / Veteran's Benefits January 2004 (Box-folder 22:15)
    - Southeast Crescent Authority January 2004 (Box-folder 22:16)
    - Survivor Benefit Plan January 2004 (Box-folder 22:17)
    - Taxes January 2004 (Box-folder 22:18)
    - Tobacco Industry January 2004 (Box-folder 22:19)
    - Various January 2004 (Box-folder 22:20)
    - Coast Guard Contracting February 2004 (Box-folder 22:21)
    - Various February 2004 (Box-folder 22:22)
    - Abortion March 2004 (Box-folder 22:23)
    - Transportation March 2004 (Box-folder 22:24)
    - Various March 2004 (Box-folder 22:25)
    - Iraq April 2004 (Box-folder 22:26)
    - Millennium Challenge Account April 2004 (Box-folder 22:27)
    - Various April 2004 (Box-folder 22:28)
    - Antifreeze Safety Act May 2004 (Box-folder 23:1)
    - Millennium Challenge Account May 2004 (Box-folder 23:2)
    - Ocean View / Willoughby Shoreline Protection May 2004 (Box-folder 23:3)
    - Postal Reform May 2004 (Box-folder 23:4)
    - Small Business May 2004 (Box-folder 23:5)
    - Taxes May 2004 (Box-folder 23:6)
    - Traffic May 2004 (Box-folder 23:7)
    - Unions May 2004 (Box-folder 23:8)
    - Various May 2004 (Box-folder 23:9)
    - American Horse Slaughter Prevention Act June 2004 (Box-folder 23:10)
    - Central American Free Trade Agreement June 2004 (Box-folder 23:11)
    - Credit Unions June 2004 (Box-folder 23:12)
    - Draft Bill June 2004 (Box-folder 23:13)
    - Energy June 2004 (Box-folder 23:14)
    - Environment / Conservation June 2004 (Box-folder 23:15)
    - Fair Labor June 2004 (Box-folder 23:16)
    - Gay Marriage June 2004 (Box-folder 23:17)
    - Gun Control June 2004 (Box-folder 23:18)
    - HDTV June 2004 (Box-folder 23:19)
    - Health Care June 2004 (Box-folder 23:20)
    - Higher Education June 2004 (Box-folder 23:21)
    - Iraq June 2004 (Box-folder 23:22)
    - Media Rights June 2004 (Box-folder 23:23)
    - Public Schools June 2004 (Box-folder 23:24)
    - Social Security June 2004 (Box-folder 23:25)
    - Social Security / Medicare June 2004 (Box-folder 23:26)
    - Stock Option Accounting Reform Act June 2004 (Box-folder 23:27)
    - Transportation June 2004 (Box-folder 23:28)
    - Unions June 2004 (Box-folder 23:29)
    - Various June 2004 (Box-folder 23:30)
    - Airline Security July 2004 (Box-folder 23:31)
    - American Horse Slaughter Prevention Act July 2004 (Box-folder 23:32)
    - Credit Unions July 2004 (Box-folder 23:33)
    - Environment July 2004 (Box-folder 23:34)
    - Gay Marriage July 2004 (Box-folder 23:35)
    - Gun Control July 2004 (Box-folder 23:36)
    - Health Care July 2004 (Box-folder 23:37)
    - Interstate Waste July 2004 (Box-folder 23:38)
    - Junk Fax Prevention July 2004 (Box-folder 23:39)
    - Media Rights July 2004 (Box-folder 23:40)
    - Medical Research / Funding July 2004 (Box-folder 23:41)
    - Military / Veteran's Benefits July 2004 (Box-folder 23:42)
    - Social Security / Medicare July 2004 (Box-folder 23:43)
    - Terrorism July 2004 (Box-folder 23:44)
    - Transportation July 2004 (Box-folder 23:45)
    - Workplace Religious Freedom Act July 2004 (Box-folder 23:46)
    - Various July 2004 (Box-folder 23:47)
    - American Horse Slaughter Prevention Act August 2004 (Box-folder 24:1)
    - Child Custody Protection Act August 2004 (Box-folder 24:2)
    - Concurrent Receipt of Military and Retired Pay and VA Disability Compensation August 2004 (Box-folder 24:3)
    - Credit Unions August 2004 (Box-folder 24:4)
    - Fair Labor August 2004 (Box-folder 24:5)
    - Gay Marriage August 2004 (Box-folder 24:6)
    - Health Care August 2004 (Box-folder 24:7)
    - Sandbridge Beach Protection August 2004 (Box-folder 24:8)
    - Social Security August 2004 (Box-folder 24:9)
    - Social Security / Medicare August 2004 (Box-folder 24:10)
    - Stem Cell Research August 2004 (Box-folder 24:11)
    - Survivor Benefit Plan August 2004 (Box-folder 24:12)
    - Taxes August 2004 (Box-folder 24:13)
    - Terrorism August 2004 (Box-folder 24:14)
    - Tobacco Industry August 2004 (Box-folder 24:15)
    - Transportation August 2004 (Box-folder 24:16)
    - Various August 2004 (Box-folder 24:17)
    - Abortion September 2004 (Box-folder 24:18)
    - Airline Security September 2004 (Box-folder 24:19)
    - Child Custody Protection Act September 2004 (Box-folder 24:20)
    - Constitution Restoration Act September 2004 (Box-folder 24:21)
    - District of Columbia Personal Protection Act September 2004 (Box-folder 24:22)
    - Draft Bill September 2004 (Box-folder 24:23)
    - Fair Labor September 2004 (Box-folder 24:24)
    - Filipino World War II Veterans September 2004 (Box-folder 24:25)
    - Gay Marriage September 2004 (Box-folder 24:26)
    - Gun Control September 2004 (Box-folder 24:27)
    - Hate Crimes September 2004 (Box-folder 24:28)
    - Health Care September 2004 (Box-folder 24:29)
    - Houses of Worship Free Speech Restoration Act September 2004 (Box-folder 24:30)
    - Immigration / Migrant Workers September 2004 (Box-folder 24:31)
    - Local Law Enforcement Act September 2004 (Box-folder 24:32)
    - Native Americans September 2004 (Box-folder 24:33)
    - Pledge of Allegiance September 2004 (Box-folder 24:34)
    - Survivor Benefit Plan September 2004 (Box-folder 24:35)
    - Ten Commandments Display September 2004 (Box-folder 24:36)
    - Tobacco Industry September 2004 (Box-folder 24:37)
    - Various September 2004 (Box-folder 24:38)
    - Survivor Benefit Plan October 2004 (Box-folder 25:1)
    - U.S.S. Bristol October 2004 (Box-folder 25:2)
    - Various October 2004 (Box-folder 25:3)
    - Gay Marriage 2004 (Box-folder 25:4)
    - Interstate Waste 2004 (Box-folder 25:5)
    - Social Security / Medicare 2004 (Box-folder 25:6)
    - Various 2004 (Box-folder 25:7)
    - Various Letters from Constituents 2004 (Box-folder 25:8)
  - Petitions from Constituents 2001-2004
    This sub-series contains petitions from constituents to Ed Schrock regarding various issues including, but not limited to: abortion, animal welfare, campaign finance reform, cancer research, family planning, gay marriage, hate crimes, health care, illegal immigrants, Medicare, military and veteran's benefits, social security, and various other topics.
    - Abortion 2001 (Box-folder 26:1)
    - Animal Welfare Act 2001 (Box-folder 26:2)
    - Campaign Finance Reform -- Shays-Meehan 2001 (Box-folder 26:3)
    - Concurrent Receipt for Military / Veteran Benefits, HR 303 2001 (Box-folder 26:4)
    - Family Planning 2001 (Box-folder 26:5)
    - Medicare Reform 2001 (Box-folder 26:6)
    - National Park Conservation 2001 (Box-folder 26:7)
    - Social Security 2001 (Box-folder 26:8)
    - After School Programs 2002 (Box-folder 26:9)
    - Citizens Self Defense Act, HR 31 2002 (Box-folder 26:10)
    - Hate Crimes 2002 (Box-folder 26:11)
    - Houses of Worship and Politics 2002 (Box-folder 26:12)
    - Social Security 2002 (Box-folder 26:13)
    - Taxes 2002 (Box-folder 26:14)
    - Abortion 2003 (Box-folder 26:15)
    - Border Patrols, HR 277 2003 (Box-folder 26:16)
    - Cancer 2003 (Box-folder 26:17)
    - English Language Act 2003 (Box-folder 26:18)
    - Gay Marriage 2003 (Box-folder 26:19)
    - Health Care for Small Businesses, Associated Health Plan (AHP) 2003 (Box-folder 26:20)
    - National Language Act, HR 931 2003 (Box-folder 26:21)
    - Social Security and Medicare 2003 (Box-folder 26:22)
    - Translation Services for Non-English Speakers, HR 300 2003 (Box-folder 26:23)
    - Abortion 2004 (Box-folder 26:24)
    - Gay Marriage 2004 (Box-folder 26:25)
    - Translation Services for Non-English Speakers, HR 300 2004 (Box-folder 26:26)
    - Competitive Bidding for Home Medical Equipment undated (Box-folder 26:27)
    - Hate Crimes undated (Box-folder 26:28)
    - Houses of Worship and Politics undated (Box-folder 26:29)
    - Medicare undated (Box-folder 26:30)
    - Social Security undated (Box-folder 26:31)
    - Social Security and Illegal Immigrants undated (Box-folder 26:32)
  - Postcards from Constituents 2000-2004
    This sub-series contains constituent postcards on many of the topics already listed.
    Chronological
    - [Postcards] December 2000-March 2001 (Box 27)
    - [Postcards] March 2001-December 2001 (Box 28)
    - [Postcards] January 2002-December 2003 (Box 29)
    - [Postcards] January 2004-August 2004 (Box 30)
    - [Postcards] September 2004-December 2004 (Box 31)
  - Letters from Officials and Colleagues 2004
    This sub-series contains a small number of letters from other elected officials such as mayors, as well as fellow congressmen. Topics include various legislation and committee business.
    Alphabetical
    - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Restoration (Box-folder 32:1)
    - Coastal Planning 2004 (Box-folder 32:2)
    - Cypress Reunification 2004 (Box-folder 32:3)
    - Federal Navigation Project 2004 (Box-folder 32:4)
    - House Armed Services Committee 2004 (Box-folder 32:5)
    - House Reform Committee 2004 (Box-folder 32:6)
    - House Small Business Committee 2004 (Box-folder 32:7)
    - Medicare 2004 (Box-folder 32:8)
    - Various 2004 (Box-folder 32:9)
  - Letters from Ed Schrock to Constituents 2001-2004
    This sub-series contains letters and draft letters from Ed Schrock to constituents regarding various issues and legislation.
    - Various 2001 (Box-folder 32:10)
    - Medicare 2002 (Box-folder 32:11)
    - Cancer / Medicare 2003 (Box-folder 32:12)
    - East Coast Super Hornets at Naval Air Station (NAS) Oceana 2003 (Box-folder 32:13)
    - Iraq 2003 (Box-folder 32:14)
    - Military Concerns 2003 (Box-folder 32:15)
    - Military / Veteran's Benefits 2003 (Box-folder 32:16)
    - Military Reserve 2003 (Box-folder 32:17)
    - Survivor Benefit Plan (SBP) 2003 (Box-folder 32:18)
    - U.S. Naval Ship Naming 2003 (Box-folder 32:19)
    - Various 2003 (Box-folder 32:20)
    - Small Business Paperwork Relief Act of 2002 (SBPRA) 2004 (Box-folder 32:21)
  - Miscellaneous undated, 2003-2004
    This sub-series contains miscellaneous correspondence between Ed Schrock and constituents, as well as three notebooks of letters signed by Ed Schrock regarding various issues and legislation.
    - Defense Letters Signed by ELS 2003-2004 (Box 33)
    - Letters signed by Congressman Schrock, 107th Congress, Abortion - Foreign Policy undated (Box 34)
    - Letters signed by Congressman Schrock, 107th Congress, Healthcare - Veteran's Affairs undated (Box 35)
- Surveys and Public Opinion Assessment 2001-2004
  This series is divided into two sub-series that contain surveys and ballots sent by Ed Schrock to constituents to poll their opinions on various topics during his term in office from 2001 to 2004.
  - Constituent Opinion Ballots 2001-2004
    This sub-series contains constituent opinion ballots completed and returned by constituents from 2001 to 2004. Topics include, but not limited to: the economy, gas prices, gay marriage, gun control, immigration, Iraq, national defense, taxes, and other such issues.
    - Missile Defense System 2001 (Box-folder 36:1)
    - National Federation of Independent Business 2001 (Box-folder 36:2)
    - Tax Cuts 2001 (Box-folder 36:3)
    - Upcoming Issues in the 107th Congress 2001 (Box-folder 36:4)
    - Airline Security 2002 (Box-folder 36:5)
    - Immigration Reform 2002 (Box-folder 36:6)
    - Iraq 2002 (Box-folder 36:7)
    - National Federation of Independent Business 2002 (Box-folder 36:8)
    - Social Security: Personal Retirement Accounts 2002 (Box-folder 36:9)
    - Tax Cuts 2002 (Box-folder 36:10)
    - Gay Marriage 2003 (Box-folder 36:11)
    - Gas Prices 2004 (Box-folder 36:12)
    - Immigration Reform 2004 (Box-folder 36:13)
    - Associate Health Plans undated (Box-folder 36:14)
    - Ergonomics undated (Box-folder 36:15)
    - Genetically Altered Food undated (Box-folder 36:16)
    - Gun Control undated (Box-folder 36:17)
    - National Sales Tax undated (Box-folder 36:18)
  - Constituent Surveys 2003-2004
    This sub-series contains surveys completed and returned by constituents from 2003 to 2004. Two surveys are represented. One survey completed by constituents on the Eastern Shore in 2003 included questions about terrorism, prescription drugs, taxes, abortion, and education. The other from 2004 surveyed constituents about their outlook on the economy including taxes, national debt, and social security.
    - Eastern Shore Issue Survey I 2003 (Box-folder 37:1)
    - Eastern Shore Issue Survey II 2003 (Box-folder 37:2)
    - Eastern Shore Issue Survey III 2003 (Box-folder 37:3)
    - Eastern Shore Issue Survey IV 2003 (Box-folder 37:4)
    - Eastern Shore Issue Survey V 2003 (Box-folder 37:5)
    - Eastern Shore Issue Survey VI 2003 (Box-folder 37:6)
    - Eastern Shore Issue Survey VII 2003 (Box-folder 38:1)
    - Eastern Shore Issue Survey VIII 2003 (Box-folder 38:2)
    - Eastern Shore Issue Survey IX 2003 (Box-folder 38:3)
    - Eastern Shore Issue Survey X 2003 (Box-folder 38:4)
    - Eastern Shore Issue Survey XI 2003 (Box-folder 38:5)
    - Economic Outlook Survey 2004 (Box-folder 38:6)
- Committees
  During his time in Congress, Ed Schrock served on the House Armed Services Committee, House Budget Committee, House Small Business Committee, and House Reforms Committee. The only committee represented to any extent within this collection is the House Small Business Committee. The Small Business Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform and Oversight is a subcommittee of the House Small Business Committee. It is represented within these materials.
  - U. S. House of Representatives Committee on Small Business 2003-2004
    This series contains seven notebooks of committee and subcommittee hearing materials from Ed Schrock's time on the U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Small Business. Topics include: improvements to the Small Business Office of Advocacy, regulations in the travel industry that affect small business, contract bundling and small business procurement, the effect of e-mail spam effect on small business, small businesses and the environment, labor enforcement against small businesses, and reforming labor regulations to keep small businesses competitive.
    - Improving and Strengthening the SBA Office of Advocacy, Subcommittee Hearing, U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Small Business 1 April 2003 (Box 39)
    - CRS Regulations and Small Business in the Travel Industry, U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Small Business 26 June 2003 (Box 40)
    - Contract Building and Small Business Procurement, U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Small Business 15 July 2003 (Box 41)
    - E-mail Spam and its Effects on Small Business, U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Small Business, Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform and Oversight 30 October 2003 (Box 42)
    - Small Businesses Creating Jobs and Protecting the Environment, U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Small Business, Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform and Oversight 22 April 2004 (Box 43)
    - Department of Labor Enforcement Against Small Businesses, June 17, 2004, U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Small Business, Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform and Oversight 17 June 2004 (Box 44)
    - Reforming Regulation to Keep America's Small Businesses Competitive, U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Small Business, Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform and Oversight 20 May 2004 (Box 45)
- Reference Materials
  This series contains various reference materials that may have been used by Ed Schrock to determine his stand on many issues, or to back up his position. Six sub-series consist of brochures, booklets, and handbooks; conference materials; legislative materials including bill summaries, voting records, and legislative profiles; magazines and journals; news articles and press clippings; and government reports and assessments.
  - Brochures, Booklets, and Handbooks 2003
    This sub-series contains brochures, booklets, and handbooks related to the Air Force and jet specifications. Materials are from the 108th Congress
    - Air Force Handbook 108th Congress - First Session (Box-folder 46:1)
    - FY03 Congressional Overview - Lockheed Martin Aeronautics Company 2003? (Box-folder 46:2)
  - Conference Materials 15-17 September 2003
    This sub-series contains a program from a military volunteer forces conference
    - All Volunteer Force: 30 Years of Service Conference 15-17 September 2003 (Box-folder 46:3)
  - Legislative Materials 2001-2004
    This sub-series contains legislative materials such as bill summaries, legislative profiles, legislative activity guides, voting records, and a list of bill sponsored or co-sponsored by Ed Schrock.
    - Bill Summaries 2003 (Box-folder 46:4)
    - Port Security Grants (Box-folder 46:5)
    - Legislative Profiles for the 107th Congress 3 January 2001-31 December 2002 (Box 47)
    - Legislative Activity Guide, 108th Congress, 1st Session January-June 2003 (Box 48)
    - Voting Record - 107th Congress (Box 49)
    - Bills sponsored / co-sponsored by Congressman Schrock, 107th Congress, Abortion -- Guns (Box 50)
    - Bills sponsored / co-sponsored by Congressman Schrock, 107th Congress, Healthcare -- Resources (Box 51)
    - Bills sponsored / co-sponsored by Congressman Schrock, 107th Congress, Space -- Taxes (Box 52)
    - Bills sponsored / co-sponsored by Congressman Schrock, 107th Congress, Technology -- Welfare (Box 53)
    - Department of Defense Issues 108th Congress (Box 54)
    - Defense Policy Archives 108th Congress, Rep. Ed Schrock (Box 55)
  - Magazines and Journals 2002-2004
    This sub-series contains military magazines and journals.
    - Armed Forces Journal July 2004 (Box-folder 56:1)
    - Marines Almanac 2002 (Box-folder 56:2)
    - Operation Iraqi Freedom undated (Box-folder 56:3)
    - The United States Coast Guard -- The Shield of Freedom 2004 (Box-folder 56:4)
  - Press Clippings and News Articles 2001-2004
    This sub-series contains news clippings and articles on a variety of issues. Included are six notebooks of clippings and articles (many from electronic sources), and assorted folders related to Iraq and the Panama Canal.
    - Iraq (Box-folder 56:5)
    - Iraq -- Pneumonia Cases of U.S. Soldiers in Iraq (Box-folder 56:6)
    - Panama Canal 2001 (Box-folder 56:7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 56:8)
    - ELS Press Clippings, Part 1 2001 (Box 57)
    - ELS Press Clippings, Part 2 2001 (Box 58)
    - ELS Press Clippings 2002 (Box 59)
    - ELS Press Clippings 2003 (Box 60)
    - ELS Press Clippings, Part 1 2004 (Box 61)
    - ELS Press Clippings, Part 2 2004 (Box 62)
  - Reports 2001-2004
    This sub-series contains reports and assessments. Included are materials on Iraq, the U.S.S. Cole attack, terrorism, a financial report for the Army National Guard, and various other topics.
    - The Army National Guard Annual Financial Report, Fiscal Year 2002 2002? (Box-folder 63:1)
    - Iraq (Box-folder 63:2)
    - Iraq (Pre-War) (Box-folder 63:3)
    - Iraq -- CPA Notes and Information (Post-War) I (Box-folder 63:4)
    - Iraq -- CPA Notes and Information (Post-War) II (Box-folder 63:5)
    - Iraq -- Operation Iraqi-Freedom: A First-Blush Assessment (Box-folder 63:6)
    - The Spirit of Enterprise: U.S. Chamber of Commerce (Box-folder 63:7)
    - Transfer of National Defense Reserve Fleet Vessels from the James River Reserve Fleet for Disposal at Able UK Facilities, Teesside, UK: Environmental Assessment 29 June 2004 (Box-folder 64:1)
    - United States General Accounting Office Report to Congressional Committees: Combating Terrorism: Selected Challenges and Related Recommendations September 2001 (Box-folder 64:2)
    - U.S.S. Cole Attack (Box-folder 64:3)
- Miscellaneous 2001-2004
  This series contains miscellaneous material that did not fit under other series headings. Included are: Congress of the United State stationary, photos and photo CDs, and a 3 floppy disk of files including media releases, advisories, speeches, letters, and photos.
  - Congress of the United States Stationary (Box-folder 64:4)
  - Curriculum Vita, Ann L. Stanford, Ph.D. (Box-folder 64:5)
  - 107th Files (Media Releases, Advisories, Speeches, Letters, Pictures), Data CD (Box-folder 64:6)
  - Schrock Press Releases 2004, Data Disk (Box-folder 64:7)
  - Interoffice Memo, Leave Balances 26 October 2001 (Box-folder 64:8)
  - Photos (Box-folder 64:9)
  - CNRF (Commander Navy Reserve Force) Awards undated, Photo CD (Box-folder 64:10)
  - Codel Saxton 1-4 December 2003, Photo CD (Box-folder 64:11)
  - Navy Seals undated, Photo CD (Box-folder 64:12)
  - Pentagon Pics, Photo CD (Box-folder 64:13)
  - SOCOM Codel 2 December 2003, Photo CD (Box-folder 64:14)
  - Special Ops Trip December 2003, Photo CD (Box-folder 64:15)